<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>John Forrester on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/john-forrester/</link><description>Recent content in John Forrester on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/john-forrester/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Local and Regional Authorities can improve their ransomware defenses</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/12/19/blog_regional_ransomware_defense/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/12/19/blog_regional_ransomware_defense/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="how-local-and-regional-authorities-can-improve-their-ransomware-defenses">How Local and Regional Authorities can improve their ransomware defenses&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A recent study done by the National Association of State CIOs (NASCiO) and Deloitte found in the US 75% of state CISOs view ransomware as a threat. As this Govloop report reported “…there’s good reason for that. A number of factos, the report notes that combine to make local and regional governments particularly vulnerable to this attack”.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>High impact: Ransomeware is capable of causing an organization’s operations to a halt. As an attack it is one of the most likely facing local and regional organizations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easy entry: With commercialization of attacks using “Ransomware-as-a-Service”, even non-technical threat actors are able to profit easily from ransomware operations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Emergence of distributors: Malware families tend to be, the Govloop article points out, prolific information stealers are linked to various ransomware operators.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Clearly local and regional organizations need to revamp their strategies to deal with these challenges:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Users are not stupid</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_users-are-not-stupid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_users-are-not-stupid/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="users-are-not-stupid">Users are not stupid&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This article from Julie Haney of NIST deals with some of the misconceptions and pitfalls that cyber security professionals fall victim to. These pitfalls reflect a tendency in the cyber security community “to focus and depend on technology to solve today’s security problems while at the same time failing to appreciate the human element: the individual and social factors affecting security adoption.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To appreciate the importance of the human element in cyber security, Haney suggests it would be best to understand the concepts of usability and usable cyber security.
The International Organization for Standardization definition of usability is ‘the extent to which people can use systems, products, and services with effectiveness, efficiency, and satisfaction to accomplish their goals in a specified context of use’.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why old school thinking?</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_why-old-school-thinking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_why-old-school-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-old-school-thinking">Why old school thinking?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For many years, a report from Govloop in the US writes, government agencies have applied a “hodgepodge of cyber-security strategies” to counter both internal and external risks. Many relied on firewalls to manage external activity and potential threats. In the end, the Govloop authors conclude that Legacy firewalls tend to be more concerned with activity attempting to penetrate their perimeter defenses and do not monitor internal activities within the local network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions III</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/17/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/17/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="cybersecurity-for-public-utilities-solutions-iii">Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions III&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Failing to understand the gravity of the potential effects of a power grid attack leaves municipal utility companies unprepared to enact the necessary cybersecurity counter-measures necessary to prevent or, at least, mitigate attacks. As Miller [1], points out, local governments could benefit from the information that would lead to the early prevention of cyberattacks. Unfortunately, the information is often hidden or never revealed. Although municipalities are obliged to report attacks in a timely fashion, they often avoid reporting attacks to maintain credibility. Nor do they necessarily see sharing of information about attacks as useful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions II</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/11/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/11/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="cybersecurity-for-public-utilities-solutions-ii">Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions II&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cyberattacks launched on municipal utility companies are similar to attacks in any other industry. However, the potential for OT attacks and the dangers of a major service disruption has raised the stakes. Miller outlines in this article [1] the most common cybersecurity attacks that have affected municipal utility companies. &lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="denial-of-service">Denial of Service &lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Attacks that stop users from accessing essential networks are typically referred to as denial of service (DoS) or distributed denial of service (DDoS) attacks. A DoS attack is initiated by a single attacking computer. A DDoS attack is launched by multiple attacking devices. While the attack is in progress, companies can&amp;rsquo;t access the means to provide services. These attacks have serious implications for any company, but the interruption of essential services like electricity or running water can quickly become disastrous.  Unfortunately, given the lack of training many utilities are particularly vulnerable to denial of service attacks. While these attacks are difficult to deal with, more work on raising an awareness of the issues and possible counter-measures would be invaluable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="cybersecurity-for-public-utilities-solutions-i">Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 2021 Jason Miller wrote an article on cybersecurity for municipal utilities stressing that cyber-attacks were increasing every year and greatly impacting a wide range of high-profile targets from governmental agencies to financial and insurance organizations, hospitals and other health facilities, and educational institutions. Of particular concern in many countries, he points out, is the situation on local levels where local governments with municipal utilities are often under-funded with poorly trained staff [1]. Unfortunately, the solutions he offers do not take into account the range of problems facing municipal utilities. Many are not aware, however, of how municipal utilities have become targets for “nation-state actors” and the possibly disastrous effects of an attack.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>