<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Italy on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/italy/</link><description>Recent content in Italy on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/italy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Digital Transformation in Italian Local Authorities: Progress Made, but Cybersecurity Lags Behind</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/06/12/blog_italian_companies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/06/12/blog_italian_companies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, Italy’s local governments have taken significant steps toward digital transformation. Fuelled by national reforms and EU recovery funds, more and more municipalities are bringing services online. Yet as digital adoption accelerates, a critical vulnerability has emerged: cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="a-more-digital-italyeven-at-the-local-level"&gt;A More Digital Italy—Even at the Local Level?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital innovation is no longer the exclusive domain of central ministries or major cities. Local governments across Italy are embracing new technologies at an unprecedented pace. The data speaks for itself:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity in Italian Municipalities: A Growing Emergency</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/03/31/blog_cybsec_italian_munc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/03/31/blog_cybsec_italian_munc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the digitalization of Public Administration has increasingly exposed the
cybersecurity vulnerabilities of Italian municipalities. Hacker attacks are multiplying, targeting public
offices and essential services, while institutions struggle to respond with new regulations and
protective measures. However, the problems persist, and municipalities often find themselves
unprepared in the face of increasingly sophisticated threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rising Concern Over Cybersecurity in Municipalities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to data from the National Cybersecurity Agency (ACN), in 2024 about 18% of
cyberattacks targeted Public Administration, particularly affecting local authorities and healthcare
centers. This alarming trend prompted the government to respond with legislative measures and
security strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>