<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Christian Luidold on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/christian-luidold/</link><description>Recent content in Christian Luidold on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/christian-luidold/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NIS2 – Key Challenges on the Horizon</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/04/25/nis-challenges/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/04/25/nis-challenges/</guid><description>NIS2 – Key Challenges on the Horizon About ten years ago the proposal of the original NIS-Directive was introduced into our lives. It was the first cybersecurity act in the EU, creating a new baseline for cybersecurity. Unfortunately the effects of the original NIS weren&amp;rsquo;t as good as initially hoped. Its objectives of increasing the level of security of network and information systems across the union were hindered by problems regarding different levels of resilience among member states, insufficient resilience of individual organisations, and ineffective oversight by government authorities.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity – a case for advanced decision models</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/08/cs_aware_next_decision_models/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/08/cs_aware_next_decision_models/</guid><description>Cybersecurity – a case for advanced decision models Advanced attacks demand advanced countermeasures. On a technical level there already is an elevated level of awareness and readiness. That is why in a first wave of attacks criminals usually focus on tricking users into opening up systems for them . While this has now been the rule for at least over a decade, the way in which these attacks are prepared now follow an almost military style approach.</description></item></channel></rss>