<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>InnoSec on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/innosec/</link><description>Recent content in InnoSec on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/innosec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Inside the Mind of a Hacker: What Cyberthreat Intelligence Reveals</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/28/blog_innosec_inside_the_mind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/28/blog_innosec_inside_the_mind/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how cybersecurity experts know what hackers are planning? The answer lies in cyberthreat intelligence, a behind-the-scenes field that’s less about flashy firewalls and more about detective work. It’s like digital espionage, where analysts gather clues from hacker forums, dark web marketplaces, malware samples, and even leaked chats to understand who the attackers are, what they want, and how they operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyberthreat intelligence (CTI) helps organisations move from reacting to attacks to preventing them. By studying patterns in past breaches and monitoring hacker chatter, analysts can anticipate which industries or vulnerabilities might be targeted next. For example, if threat actors start discussing exploits in popular remote work tools, CTI teams can alert companies to patch those systems before an attack happens. This proactive approach saves time, money, and trust.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity Crystal Ball: Predicting the Next Big Cyberthreat</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/22/blog_innosec_cybersec_crystal_ball/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/22/blog_innosec_cybersec_crystal_ball/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks often seem to come out of nowhere, but behind the scenes, teams of cybersecurity experts are constantly scanning for warning signs. Through a process known as threat forecasting, analysts look at patterns in data, emerging technologies, hacker conversations, and even geopolitical shifts to predict what types of cyberattacks might happen next. It’s not magic, it’s cyberthreat intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like weather forecasting, predicting cyber threats relies on spotting trends early. If hackers begin experimenting with new tactics or tools, those clues often surface first in obscure corners of the internet, like dark web forums or malware code repositories. Cybersecurity analysts collect and analyse this data to identify new techniques before they become widespread, giving companies and users a head start in defending themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Fileless present of Malware and its evolving ML based detection, classification and prevention</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/05/28/blog_innosec_fileless_present_of_malware/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/05/28/blog_innosec_fileless_present_of_malware/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The main approach for detection and prevention of malware is based upon the concept of file signatures. More specifically, the AV solutions are scanning the system’s storage devices and hash files at process/creation time. Then they compare each of these hashes with their respective curated database which contains signatures of known malware samples. If there is a match then the file is flagged as malicious and subsequent actions take place to contain it. But what could happen if there was some kind of malware that did not rely on a file to accomplish its mission?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Risk of Misinformation and Disinformation in Cyber Threat Intelligence Communities</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/05/27/blog_innosec_misinformation_disinformation_in_cti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/05/27/blog_innosec_misinformation_disinformation_in_cti/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The ever-growing digital landscape presents organisations with a double-edged sword: vast amounts of data on cyber threats and the challenge of sifting through it all. Here&amp;rsquo;s where &lt;strong&gt;Cyber Threat Intelligence (CTI)&lt;/strong&gt; comes in. By analysing attacker behaviour and uncovering early signs of attacks, CTI empowers organisations to proactively defend themselves. However, a significant hurdle exists: &lt;strong&gt;misinformation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This misinformation comes in two forms: &lt;strong&gt;accidental mistakes&lt;/strong&gt; (misinformation) and &lt;strong&gt;deliberate deception&lt;/strong&gt; (disinformation). Both pose serious threats to CTI&amp;rsquo;s effectiveness, eroding trust in shared intelligence and weakening cybersecurity defences.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>