<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CS-CONNECT on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/cs-connect/</link><description>Recent content in CS-CONNECT on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/cs-connect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CS-Connect first steps!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/08/cs-connect-first-steps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/08/cs-connect-first-steps/</guid><description>&lt;p>CS-Connect first steps!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you may remember, one of the many exciting outcomes of CS-AWARE-NEXT is the collaboration platform that has been baptized CS-Connect in the Wien meeting!
CS-Connect is a collaboration layer for the ecosystem, aimed to support the organisations in their activities toward improved security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have collected the requirements and are now deciding what is the current basis for the development and overcoming different technological challenges. We have selected several Open Collaboration Platforms (CPs) to study and evaluate. The objective is to select the one that is best suitable for us to build CS-Connect on top, using the traditional and well-established open source development model of “Standing on the shoulder of giants” which is to guarantee quick prototyping, software stability and resiliency, as well as sustainability of complex software projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome CS-Connect!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/12/15/cs_aware_next_cs_connect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/12/15/cs_aware_next_cs_connect/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="welcome-cs-connect">Welcome CS-Connect!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In CS-AWARE-NEXT, the role of our unit, CERICT-Università di Salerno, is to design, develop and evaluate, a collaboration layer for the ecosystem, aimed to support the organisations in their activities toward improved security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are actually collecting all the requirements from the use cases and we have had very interesting discussions with the organisations in the ecosystems in Larissa and in Foggia, to find out what is actually needed to ensure adequate support to the ecosystem. And indeed, we have collected quite a few requirements, some of which were expected by us (aren’t we all collaborating on something after all) but many were surprising and stimulating. We cannot spoil them as they are going to be in the Deliverable that Workpackage 2 is creating by February 2023. For example, we cannot tell you that we are considering different scenarios that involve the ecosystem in different activities, with different tools and different support by the collaboration system. As well as we cannot tell you that a flexible visibility mechanism for the information shared will allow to accommodate different ecosystem with diverse cohesion. And, of course, we cannot tell you that the visualization of the system will be based on the CS-AWARE visualization but contextualized with the goal of the scenario. Sorry.
What we can tell you now is what is the name of the tool!
In fact, during the General Meeting in Wien, stimulated by the words, dubiously attributed to the Bard of Avon:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>