<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Podcast on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/podcast/</link><description>Recent content in Podcast on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 ερωτήσεις – 3 απαντήσεις: Our popular CS-AWARE podcast series of 3 questions – 3 answers now in other languages</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We start today with a podcast in Greek with Elisavet Goutman, Business Development and Marketing Manager of OTS in Greece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce the fourth podcast with Elisavet Goutman of OTS Greece.
The reason we shall experiment with podcasts in national languages, namely not in English is rather simple: English can be our common working language for Deliverables, and can be ideal for reaching out researchers, but if we truly want to walk the last mile and increase the visibility of the project to a large audience in the participating countries, then the best is to create content in the different national languages.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers: Starting up for 2023 with a discussion on ‘AI, the Universe and Everything’ with two Datrix C-level executives</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce the third podcast with Pierluigi Vacca and Matteo Bregonzio of Datrix, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pierluigi Vacca, after a 3-year experience with Google USA as Search Quality Evaluator (analysis of search queries and site positioning to improve the Google algorithm) in 2004 he took part in the start-up of Google Italy as manager of Italian and international key accounts, connecting activities as marketing &amp;amp; communication strategies, data intelligence and customers acquisition/retention. In 2010 Pierluigi joined ex-googlers to launch a new start-up - 3rdPlace - , focused on digital intelligence, where he worked as head of operations. That start up is now part of a bigger group of international tech companies - Datrix - where Pierluigi is Chief Product Officer, leading activities from business idea generation to design-thinking-based product development and go-to-market strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers Christmas 2022 edition: The second CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce the second CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast with Juha Röning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Juha is the Coordinator of the CS-AWARE-NEXT project and is Professor of Embedded Systems at the University of Oulu. Juha has also coordinated the original CS-AWARE project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has three patents and has published more than 300 papers in the areas of computer vision, robotics, intelligent signal analysis, and software security. He is currently serving as a Board of Director for euRobotics aisbl. He is also a steering board member of ARTMIS-IA.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce the first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast with Chris Wills!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris is Founder and Member of the Management Board of the CS-AWARE Corporation, and has worked as a member of the CS-AWARE project, leading the socio-technical analysis of the cybersecurity situations in the two major European cities that were partners in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His specialist areas of interest are those of Socio-Technical systems analysis and design of cybersecurity systems, software process in safety critical systems and threat and risk assessment in ITC systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>