<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</guid><description>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I In 2021 Jason Miller wrote an article on cybersecurity for municipal utilities stressing that cyber-attacks were increasing every year and greatly impacting a wide range of high-profile targets from governmental agencies to financial and insurance organizations, hospitals and other health facilities, and educational institutions. Of particular concern in many countries, he points out, is the situation on local levels where local governments with municipal utilities are often under-funded with poorly trained staff [1].</description></item><item><title>Welcome CS-Connect!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/12/15/cs_aware_next_cs_connect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/12/15/cs_aware_next_cs_connect/</guid><description>Welcome CS-Connect! In CS-AWARE-NEXT, the role of our unit, CERICT-Università di Salerno, is to design, develop and evaluate, a collaboration layer for the ecosystem, aimed to support the organisations in their activities toward improved security.
We are actually collecting all the requirements from the use cases and we have had very interesting discussions with the organisations in the ecosystems in Larissa and in Foggia, to find out what is actually needed to ensure adequate support to the ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Startups in Europe – and elsewhere</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/27/cs_aware_next_startups_in_europe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/27/cs_aware_next_startups_in_europe/</guid><description>Startups in Europe – and elsewhere CS-AWARE Corporation is not only one of the partners of the CS-AWARE-NEXT Consortium, but also the main vehicle for the exploitation of all project outcomes and results. The company itself is a successful spin-out of the previous CS-AWARE Innovation Action and considered as a success story because we exhibited commitment to build a sustainable business that will help local public organisations increase their awareness and build capacities to successfully fight with cyber security threats.</description></item><item><title>Podcasts</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 12:42:58 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast We are happy to announce the first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast with Chris Wills!
Chris is Founder and Member of the Management Board of the CS-AWARE Corporation, and has worked as a member of the CS-AWARE project, leading the socio-technical analysis of the cybersecurity situations in the two major European cities that were partners in the project.
His specialist areas of interest are those of Socio-Technical systems analysis and design of cybersecurity systems, software process in safety critical systems and threat and risk assessment in ITC systems.</description></item><item><title>Turning the Internet into a meaningful (data) space!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/05/cs_aware_next_turning_internet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/05/cs_aware_next_turning_internet/</guid><description>Turning the Internet into a meaningful (data) space! Last week I attended the works of the 1st International Conference on FAIR Digital Objects. One may wonder what FAIR Digital Objects are – and then visit the Web page of the Fair Digital Objects Forum to learn more.
Before entering the details of what FDOs are, it may be worth to spend some little time and explain what FAIR is about. More and more projects and research ‘endeavours’ and ‘ventures’ take it as a prerequisite, that all data to be collected – processed – managed – stored should be FAIR.</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 12:42:58 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/events/</guid><description>AI4Future 21 October 2022 Via Santa Maria in Gradi, 4 01100 Viterbo 🇪🇺The EU funded Horizon project CS-AWARE-NEXT, that will take part to AI4FUTURE and present an innovative cybersecurity framework to better address a dynamic and constantly changing landscape.
CS-AWARE-NEXT provides local supply chain dependencies with a socio-technical support for local/regional cooperation and collaboration, since the local/regional level is currently not considered in the multi-level cybersecurity framework established by the 2013/2020 European cybersecurity strategy and the NIS/NIS2 directive.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity infrastructures - 'Ferrari fast and Fiat cheap'</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/27/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/27/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</guid><description>Cybersecurity infrastructures - &amp;lsquo;Ferrari fast and Fiat cheap&amp;rsquo; The title of this blog may seem deliberately provocative but it is actually not meant at all as such. We could also have used some other car brand – so we could have named the blog: ‘Why not buy a Porsche and pay the price of a Volkswagen Polo?’ The original ‘Ferrari fast and Fiat cheap’ idea comes from Alberto Savoia and a presentation he made about ‘How to Succeed by Failing ‘Ferrari Fast’’ which you can listen to as a podcast here.</description></item><item><title>A great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT?</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</guid><description>A great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT? Don&amp;rsquo;t remember if have heard of this incident before, but this could actually be a great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT. It is about the May 2021 ransomware attack on the Health Service Executive (HSE).
At the end of the year 2021, a report was published, that had been commissioned by the Health Services Executive (“HSE”). The report counts about 100 pages – so it is not what one might regard as a convenient reading for an evening discussion.</description></item><item><title>The hard thing about impact</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/13/cs_aware_next_the_hard_thing_about_impact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/13/cs_aware_next_the_hard_thing_about_impact/</guid><description>The hard thing about impact It is now over 8 years that the ‘Hard Thing about Hard Things’ has become a best-selling reader on entrepreneurship. The reason that the audience liked the book may be because the author is not afraid to take for granted that mistakes happen and are an inevitable, or as I prefer to call: a ‘shadow capital’ for every enterprise and venture.
Ben Horowitz, the author of the books, is apart from businessman and investor also active as blogger, devoting time and energy to communicate his ideas and also have them tested with a wider audience.</description></item><item><title>The world is changing…</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/05/cs_aware_next_the_world_is_changing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/05/cs_aware_next_the_world_is_changing/</guid><description>The world is changing… … and startups are considered as agents of change.
Young people now, as well as less young ones, quit their jobs ‘en masse’ and find substance and what each of us may understand in our own, individual ways as ‘meaning in life’ – this is what became to get known as the Great Resignation or the Big Quit.
Many of us have been praised within conservative education and life cultures, feeling that taking risks is worth once you have a big organisation to support you.</description></item><item><title>Another attack…</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/cs_aware_next_another_attack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/cs_aware_next_another_attack/</guid><description>Another attack… Last week, another attack against the UK&amp;rsquo;s National Health Service: this time the target was the NHS 111, a hot line helps people get the right advice and treatment when they urgently need it. So it is not about cinema ticket reservations or something else that one would consider as less important, less critical or less urgent.
You can read about this here and here. So it is nothing new at all – same attacks took place last May in Carinthia in Austria.</description></item><item><title>CS-AWARE Next Project successfully launched!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/08/23/cs_aware_next_launched/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/08/23/cs_aware_next_launched/</guid><description>CS-AWARE Next Project successfully launched!! A new Horizon Europe research project to help organisations and local &amp;amp; regional networks improve cybersecurity awareness and collaboration.
A pan-European consortium led by the University of Oulu in Finland has successfully launched a new Horizon Europe project. The project is called CS-AWARE-NEXT and builds on the legacy of the CS-AWARE project, that was part of the Horizon 2020 Programme, a predecessor of Horizon Europe. The project application has been been successfully evaluated for all three dimensions related to scientific excellence, societal and economic impact and the quality of the research plan implementation.</description></item><item><title>Hello world!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/04/28/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/04/28/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello world! Welcome to join our journey with CS-AWARE-NEXT, a cyber security research project funded by European Union&amp;rsquo;s Horizon Europe research and innovation programme! We will be updating the project&amp;rsquo;s progress and informing you about our arranged events and achieved results in this page with brief blog posts. If you are interested to follow our progress, make sure to follow us on Twitter to get notified when new posts are added so you don&amp;rsquo;t miss them!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/publications/pub1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/publications/pub1/</guid><description>Publication placeholder This is a placeholder</description></item><item><title>Consortium</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/consortium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/consortium/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Want to hear more more about the project? Feel free to contact the project consortium members if you want to hear more about the project or participate in the workshops and events.
For media inquiries, please contact the project coordinator.</description></item><item><title>Impact</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_impact/</guid><description>The main vehicle for exploitation of the CS-AWARE-NEXT project results (and thus the project’s pathways to impact) is the CS-AWARE Corporation, which intends to bring the project results to the market in the context of the CS-AWARE cybersecurity awareness and management platform. For further dissemination of project results, academic partners have interest in creating educational and research impact, while SMEs and industry partners have interest in advancing technological achievements and advancing the market introduction of project results.</description></item><item><title>Objectives</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_objectives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_objectives/</guid><description>Objective 1: Improved organisational policy support for dynamic cybersecurity management Description: Provide a cybersecurity management policy framework for organizations to better address the dynamic and constantly changing cybersecurity landscape. This includes a tighter integration between classical risk management and incident management tasks, in order to e.g. be able to more dynamically manage disaster recovery and business continuity after an incident. Collaboration within the organization (between different departments) and with other actors in the multi-level European cybersecurity framework, starting from actors in the local/regional supply chain to actors and authorities on the national/European level, is an important aspect to be addressed by a modern organizational cybersecurity management policy framework.</description></item><item><title>Project</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_overview/</guid><description>Overview The mission of CS-AWARE-NEXT is to address cybersecurity and collaboration within local/regional (intra-organisational and supply chain) networks, in concert with the multi-level European cybersecurity framework as defined by the European cybersecurity strategy. This is achieved through the integration of new methods and tools for provisioning of improved disaster preparedness, multi-level information sharing and advanced AI-based self-healing, to aid in recovery and business continuity of inter-dependent NIS sector organizations in an effort to better address cascading cybersecurity issues.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_publications/</guid><description>Reports and Deliverables Here you can find a list of public project reports and deliverables.
Publication link placeholder</description></item><item><title>Terms of Use</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tos/</guid><description>© CS-AWARE-NEXT Consortium, 2022-2024, all rights reserved.
Reproduction is authorised, provided the original source is acknowledged. Any restrictions on use shall be clearly indicated.
The content provided here is for general information purposes. We assume no warranty/liability for the accuracy, currency, completeness and availability of the information/services offered. In particular, no legal claims arising from the use of the information and services accessed may be established. They cannot replace comprehensive legal advice.</description></item></channel></rss>