<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Crowdstrike Falcon outage</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/07/24/blog_crowdstrike_falcon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/07/24/blog_crowdstrike_falcon/</guid><description>The Crowdstrike Falcon outage A faulty update was distributed to a cybersecurity software called The Falcon Sensor, provided by the company Crowdstrike. The botched update to the configuration files of the kernel-level vulnerability scanner caused an out-of-bounds memory read operation that resulted in affected machines booting over and over again. The fault was found and a fix was distributed within 12 hours, but damage had already been caused. Manually fixing the affected machines would take a lot longer.</description></item><item><title>Information Society is leading the battle for Cybersecurity</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/18/blog_information_society/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/18/blog_information_society/</guid><description>Information Society is leading the battle for Cybersecurity The Ministry of Digital Governance (MDG) in Greece is implementing a set of projects through Information Society for the protection of public bodies against cyberattacks.
Cybersecurity in the public sector is crucial for safeguarding sensitive information, ensuring the integrity of essential services, and maintaining public trust. Government agencies handle vast amounts of personal data and critical infrastructure, making them prime targets for cyberattacks.</description></item><item><title>The importance of user role definition and access restrictions</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_importance_of_role_definition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_importance_of_role_definition/</guid><description>The importance of user role definition and access restrictions Many of us have seen the cinematic masterpiece called The Lord of the Rings and can recall the scene where Pippin Took touches The Palantír (the glass orb looking thing with the eye of Sauron in it) and thus gave said villain an insight to his mind.
The bad news: Sauron knows everything Pippin knows. The good news: Pippin doesn’t know anything!</description></item><item><title>New investigation by Kaspersky on Cyber Attacks</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_cyberattacks_kaspersky/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_cyberattacks_kaspersky/</guid><description>New investigation by Kaspersky on Cyber Attacks Kaspersky has recently concluded an investigation into cyber-attacks targeting the industrial sector in Eastern Europe. The investigation has revealed the employment of advanced tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) by threat actors to compromise industrial organizations in the region. Industries such as manufacturing, industrial control system (ICS) engineering and integration have been particularly affected, emphasizing the urgent need for enhanced cybersecurity preparedness.
According to the research a series of targeted attacks was revealed, aiming at data -breach through the creation of a channel with similarities to cases previously reported, such as ExCone, and DexCone, a fact that clearly manifests the participation of APT31 (also known as Judgement Panda and Zirconium).</description></item><item><title>The Fileless present of Malware and its evolving ML based detection, classification and prevention</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/05/28/blog_innosec_fileless_present_of_malware/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/05/28/blog_innosec_fileless_present_of_malware/</guid><description>The Fileless present of Malware and its evolving ML based detection, classification and prevention The main approach for detection and prevention of malware is based upon the concept of file signatures. More specifically, the AV solutions are scanning the system’s storage devices and hash files at process/creation time. Then they compare each of these hashes with their respective curated database which contains signatures of known malware samples. If there is a match then the file is flagged as malicious and subsequent actions take place to contain it.</description></item><item><title>The Risk of Misinformation and Disinformation in Cyber Threat Intelligence Communities</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/05/27/blog_innosec_misinformation_disinformation_in_cti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/05/27/blog_innosec_misinformation_disinformation_in_cti/</guid><description>The Risk of Misinformation and Disinformation in Cyber Threat Intelligence Communities The ever-growing digital landscape presents organisations with a double-edged sword: vast amounts of data on cyber threats and the challenge of sifting through it all. Here&amp;rsquo;s where Cyber Threat Intelligence (CTI) comes in. By analysing attacker behaviour and uncovering early signs of attacks, CTI empowers organisations to proactively defend themselves. However, a significant hurdle exists: misinformation.
This misinformation comes in two forms: accidental mistakes (misinformation) and deliberate deception (disinformation).</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity and the Domino effect</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/12/20/cs_aware_next_dominos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/12/20/cs_aware_next_dominos/</guid><description>Cybersecurity &amp;amp; the Domino effect A cyberattack is rarely caused by one big thing, but more often a combination of many little things. We see it all the time in disaster documentary film, how even the tiniest little detail can start a chain reaction with devastating results. A chain reaction that could have been stopped if even just one of the Dominos in the line were missing.
Take documentary film about plane crashes for example.</description></item><item><title>How Local and Regional Authorities can improve their ransomware defenses</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/12/19/blog_regional_ransomware_defense/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/12/19/blog_regional_ransomware_defense/</guid><description>How Local and Regional Authorities can improve their ransomware defenses A recent study done by the National Association of State CIOs (NASCiO) and Deloitte found in the US 75% of state CISOs view ransomware as a threat. As this Govloop report reported “…there’s good reason for that. A number of factos, the report notes that combine to make local and regional governments particularly vulnerable to this attack”.
High impact: Ransomeware is capable of causing an organization’s operations to a halt.</description></item><item><title>CriM 2023</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/10/11/blog_crim23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/10/11/blog_crim23/</guid><description>CriM 2023 The Cyber Security Seminar and Workshops (CriM) has been running for 24 years. We are glad to host for three days experts on this year&amp;rsquo;s topic: Supply Chain and Cyber Security.
The mornings are filled with lectures and the afternoon workshops give practical expereince. The attendence is free of charge and 5 ECTS are available for completing the course. Please join us between 14th and 16th of November 2023 here in Oulu.</description></item><item><title>Lessons learnt from cyber-attacks on Greek municipalities</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/10/10/blog_lessions_learnt_greece/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/10/10/blog_lessions_learnt_greece/</guid><description>Lessons learnt from cyber-attacks on Greek municipalities Just how hard is to describe the importance of a service whose value the customers cannot quite comprehend or quantify in order to invest in it in the Greek public sector?
If one had to answer this question, he would have to give many answers, depending on various factors. It is incredibly difficult for an organisation to fully comprehend the need and the importance of cybersecurity service or product when he hasn’t been exposed or harmed by a cyber-attack.</description></item><item><title>New Cybersecuirty Master's Program in Oulu</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</guid><description>New Cybersecuirty Master&amp;rsquo;s Program in Oulu Cyber security is a new study option based on the research excellence in software security at the University of Oulu. The student specialising in cyber security will be able to design, develop, test and evaluate systems, software or hardware for security goals in the ever evolving digital landscape​.
As a whole, artificial intelligence and the development of different AI solutions play a role in all four study options.</description></item><item><title>New Cybersecurity Master's Program in Oulu</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/blog_new_cybersec_curri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/blog_new_cybersec_curri/</guid><description>New Cybersecurity Master&amp;rsquo;s Program in Oulu Cybersecurity is a new study option based on the research excellence in software security at the University of Oulu. The student specialising in cybersecurity will be able to design, develop, test and evaluate systems, software or hardware for security goals in the ever evolving digital landscape​.
As a whole, artificial intelligence and the development of different AI solutions play a role in all four study options.</description></item><item><title>CS-AWARE NEXT received support from the Horizon Standardisation Booster</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_standardisation_booster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_standardisation_booster/</guid><description>CS-AWARE NEXT received support from the Horizon Standardisation Booster Our project had the opportunity to receive advisory services by the HSbooster.eu that is a European Commission initiative aiming to provide expert services to European projects to help them to increase and valorise project results by contributing to the creation of new or improvement of existing standards.
As presented in the final expert report, ‘the whole HSBooster consultancy process with CS-AWARE NEXT went fluently and there was great support by the team of CS-AWARE NEXT to identify a suitable standardisation strategy for their envisioned project results’.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing your security with open-source tools</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_enhancing_security_open_source/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_enhancing_security_open_source/</guid><description>Enhancing your security with open-source tools With cybersecurity gaining increased attention in Italy, it has emerged as the top priority for digital investment among businesses in 2023. Notably, both large enterprises and SMEs recognize the significance of robust cybersecurity measures. Recent data reveals that a staggering 61% of organisations with over 250 employees have chosen to boost their cybersecurity budgets in the past year. Moreover, the Italian cybersecurity market is projected to witness remarkable growth, reaching a value of 1.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity challenges in Greek companies – Study by EY Greece and Microsoft</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/28/blog_study_ey_greece_microsoft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/28/blog_study_ey_greece_microsoft/</guid><description>Cybersecurity challenges in Greek companies – Study by EY Greece and Microsoft ΕΥ Greece and Microsoft have carried out a study on the challenges concerning cybersecurity in Greece. The study attempts, for the first time in the Greek market, to thoroughly analyse the current national and European legal and regulatory framework of cybersecurity. European regulations, such as NIS, NIS II and CERD, the main legal acts on cybersecurity in Greece (4577/2018, 4961/2022), their field of practice and the next steps for the compliance of the Greek companies with those, are presented in the study.</description></item><item><title>Συμμετοχή της ΔΕΥΑΛ στην 3η συνάντηση του Ευρωπαϊκού Προγράμματος CS-AWARE-Next στην πόλη Caltagirone της Κατάνια</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/06/23/deyal-caltagirone-gmm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/06/23/deyal-caltagirone-gmm/</guid><description>Συμμετοχή της ΔΕΥΑΛ στην 3η συνάντηση του Ευρωπαϊκού Προγράμματος CS-AWARE-Next στην πόλη Caltagirone της Κατάνια https://www.deyal.gr/el/enimerwsi/nea-anakoinwseis/item/3058-symmetoxi-tis-deval-stin-3i-synantisi-tou-evropaikoy-programmatos-cs-aware-next-stin-poli-caltagirone-tis-katania</description></item><item><title>NIS2 – Key Challenges on the Horizon</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/04/25/nis-challenges/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/04/25/nis-challenges/</guid><description>NIS2 – Key Challenges on the Horizon About ten years ago the proposal of the original NIS-Directive was introduced into our lives. It was the first cybersecurity act in the EU, creating a new baseline for cybersecurity. Unfortunately the effects of the original NIS weren&amp;rsquo;t as good as initially hoped. Its objectives of increasing the level of security of network and information systems across the union were hindered by problems regarding different levels of resilience among member states, insufficient resilience of individual organisations, and ineffective oversight by government authorities.</description></item><item><title>Data-driven cybersecurity</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/04/17/cs_aware_next_-blog_template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/04/17/cs_aware_next_-blog_template/</guid><description>Data-driven cybersecurity The availability of a large amount of data facilitates the spreading of a data-driven culture in which data are used and analyzed to support decision-making. This is also true for the cybersecurity environment in which the increasing number of threats appearing over time and related public data caused a “paradigm shift in understanding and defending against the evolving cyber attacks, from primarily reactive detection toward proactive prediction”.
Conventional data analysis approaches cannot address the complexity of the new threats and the velocity with which they are generated and spread throughout the Internet: more flexible and efficient mechanisms are needed.</description></item><item><title>Cyberattack in Thessaloniki</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_cyberattack_thessaloniki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_cyberattack_thessaloniki/</guid><description>Cyberattack in Thessaloniki Five years ago the security of the digital infrastructures of the organisations was not even an object of discussion. Most though of security as a store room with a lock on the outside, a back-up external drive, that usually remained connected on the server, and an antivirus that in most of the cases was a free one.
It comes without saying that file sharing policies, back-up check in portable devices, active directory, firewall, certified connection of the users in the internet, GDPR, website access restrictions and in everything that we today consider digital security.</description></item><item><title>Cyberattack in Thessaloniki</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_data-driven_cybersecurity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_data-driven_cybersecurity/</guid><description>Cyberattack in Thessaloniki Five years ago the security of the digital infrastructures of the organisations was not even an object of discussion. Most though of security as a store room with a lock on the outside, a back-up external drive, that usually remained connected on the server, and an antivirus that in most of the cases was a free one.
It comes without saying that file sharing policies, back-up check in portable devices, active directory, firewall, certified connection of the users in the internet, GDPR, website access restrictions and in everything that we today consider digital security.</description></item><item><title>3 ερωτήσεις – 3 απαντήσεις: Our popular CS-AWARE podcast series of 3 questions – 3 answers now in other languages</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_4/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast We start today with a podcast in Greek with Elisavet Goutman, Business Development and Marketing Manager of OTS in Greece.
We are happy to announce the fourth podcast with Elisavet Goutman of OTS Greece. The reason we shall experiment with podcasts in national languages, namely not in English is rather simple: English can be our common working language for Deliverables, and can be ideal for reaching out researchers, but if we truly want to walk the last mile and increase the visibility of the project to a large audience in the participating countries, then the best is to create content in the different national languages.</description></item><item><title>Users are not stupid</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_users-are-not-stupid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_users-are-not-stupid/</guid><description>Users are not stupid This article from Julie Haney of NIST deals with some of the misconceptions and pitfalls that cyber security professionals fall victim to. These pitfalls reflect a tendency in the cyber security community “to focus and depend on technology to solve today’s security problems while at the same time failing to appreciate the human element: the individual and social factors affecting security adoption.”
To appreciate the importance of the human element in cyber security, Haney suggests it would be best to understand the concepts of usability and usable cyber security.</description></item><item><title>Why old school thinking?</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_why-old-school-thinking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/28/blog_why-old-school-thinking/</guid><description>Why old school thinking? For many years, a report from Govloop in the US writes, government agencies have applied a “hodgepodge of cyber-security strategies” to counter both internal and external risks. Many relied on firewalls to manage external activity and potential threats. In the end, the Govloop authors conclude that Legacy firewalls tend to be more concerned with activity attempting to penetrate their perimeter defenses and do not monitor internal activities within the local network.</description></item><item><title>Greece's new Cybersecurity Bill</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/11/greece-new-cybersec-law/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/11/greece-new-cybersec-law/</guid><description>Greece&amp;rsquo;s new Cybersecurity Bill A bill on cyber security, telecommunication privacy issues and personal data has been submitted to the Greek parliament. In particular, the bill aims at “ensuring the necessary balance between privacy protection and national security, within the constitutional frame and in the foundation of the best international policies.” Additionally, the bill strengthens the “citizen’s rights against the threats that are connected to the technological evolution”.
The bill in question deals with issues of counter surveillance with the use of right tools, the foundation of Information Academy and counterintelligence and the setting of a stricter privacy frame.</description></item><item><title>CS-Connect first steps!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/08/cs-connect-first-steps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/08/cs-connect-first-steps/</guid><description>CS-Connect first steps!
As you may remember, one of the many exciting outcomes of CS-AWARE-NEXT is the collaboration platform that has been baptized CS-Connect in the Wien meeting! CS-Connect is a collaboration layer for the ecosystem, aimed to support the organisations in their activities toward improved security.
We have collected the requirements and are now deciding what is the current basis for the development and overcoming different technological challenges. We have selected several Open Collaboration Platforms (CPs) to study and evaluate.</description></item><item><title>A step towards DORA Compliance</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/07/cs_aware_next_dora_compliance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/07/cs_aware_next_dora_compliance/</guid><description>A step towards DORA Compliance Most organizations, regardless of the vertical, are often engaged in complex and massive interconnections leading to some security challenges. As a result, individual and local initiatives alone may not suffice to effectively defend against current and future threats. Indeed, more synergy and collaboration amongst companies that are “shareholders in security” hence affected by the breach from others, is essential. Recent EU cybersecurity initiatives including the NIS/NIS2 and DORA for the financial sector have ought to address the cybersecurity and resilience of both, organizations delivering essential and vital services on the one hand, and the financial services, on the other.</description></item><item><title>The legend of The Scottish Thistle - the early version of a socio-technical defence system!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/24/cs_aware_next_scottish_thistle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/24/cs_aware_next_scottish_thistle/</guid><description>The legend of The Scottish Thistle - the early version of a socio-technical defence system! Technology is getting both advanced and effective, but what good does it do if we don’t understand and use it properly? Humans have a long history of using tools to help us make our jobs easier or for keeping us safe. However, technology can only do so much on it’s own. It needs a human touch to fulfil its full potential.</description></item><item><title>Supervised vs automated response to cyberthreats</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/23/cs_aware_next_supervised_vs_automated_response/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/23/cs_aware_next_supervised_vs_automated_response/</guid><description>Supervised vs automated response to cyberthreats Cyberthreats are continually becoming more sophisticated, thus creating a demand for an equally advanced threat detection and response. Detection of cyberthreats can very much benefit from the adoption of AI, as it is able to detect attack patterns and perform correlations among various security-related events. However, when it comes to incident handling, a fully AI-enabled approach may actually cause more harm than good, due to the critical human factors involved.</description></item><item><title>Storytelling Workshops 2022</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/20/cs_aware_next_2023_storytelling_ws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/20/cs_aware_next_2023_storytelling_ws/</guid><description>Storytelling Workshops 2022 We have organised storytelling workshops in the two pilot sites of the project: the municipalities of Larissa and Foggia. Representatives of multiple public and private organisations came together for four days for these workshops that were organised by our project.
During the workshop, participants shared stories about their experiences with cybersecurity in their organisations, and, in addition, discussed real world examples of cyberattacks that had serious implications on a region, or, the term we like to use, on an entire ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity – a case for advanced decision models</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/08/cs_aware_next_decision_models/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/08/cs_aware_next_decision_models/</guid><description>Cybersecurity – a case for advanced decision models Advanced attacks demand advanced countermeasures. On a technical level there already is an elevated level of awareness and readiness. That is why in a first wave of attacks criminals usually focus on tricking users into opening up systems for them . While this has now been the rule for at least over a decade, the way in which these attacks are prepared now follow an almost military style approach.</description></item><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers: Starting up for 2023 with a discussion on ‘AI, the Universe and Everything’ with two Datrix C-level executives</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_3/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers: Starting up for 2023 with a discussion on ‘AI, the Universe and Everything’ with two Datrix C-level executives We are happy to announce the third podcast with Pierluigi Vacca and Matteo Bregonzio of Datrix, Italy.
Pierluigi Vacca, after a 3-year experience with Google USA as Search Quality Evaluator (analysis of search queries and site positioning to improve the Google algorithm) in 2004 he took part in the start-up of Google Italy as manager of Italian and international key accounts, connecting activities as marketing &amp;amp; communication strategies, data intelligence and customers acquisition/retention.</description></item><item><title>Data poisoning attacks</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/25/cs_aware_next_data_poisoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/25/cs_aware_next_data_poisoning/</guid><description>Data poisoning attacks Data poisoning is an increasingly important security concern for Machine Learning (ML) systems. As machine learning models are becoming more prevalent in our lives, they are also becoming more vulnerable to malicious attacks. Data poisoning attacks are one of the most insidious and difficult-to-detect kinds of threats on ML models.
Data poisoning is a type of adversarial attack in which a cybercriminal injects malicious data into a machine learning model.</description></item><item><title>Massive increase in cyber attacks in 2022</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/24/cs_aware_next_massive-cyber/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/24/cs_aware_next_massive-cyber/</guid><description>Massive increase in cyber attacks in 2022 Universities, research centers, state and military services, hospitals, communication infrastructure and banks have received numerous cyberattacks in 2022; and the worst is yet to come.
It is estimated that more than 1.000 cyberattacks per organisation take place throughout the universe, which is 38% more than 2021. In Europe in particular, the average number of attacks per target reached 1.000, with an increase of 26% when compared to 2021.</description></item><item><title>CriM -- Cyber Security Seminar and Workshops -- 2022</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/19/cs_aware_next_crim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/19/cs_aware_next_crim/</guid><description>CriM - Engaging the next generation of cyber security professionals During November 2022 we held the Cyber Security Seminar and Workshops in Oulu, Finland. This four days event has been held since 1999 and brings together teachers, researchers, experts, and students of cybersecurity: https://www.oulu.fi/en/crim.
CriM had twelve talks before lunch and three exercises in the afternoon, covering topics from incidence response to password handling. We were especially glad to hear a talk from Bart Preneel, Europe’s most pronounced cryptography expert, who reminded us at the end of his presentation to a quote from Immanuel Kant “Optimism is a moral duty”.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions III</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/17/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/17/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities3/</guid><description>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions III Failing to understand the gravity of the potential effects of a power grid attack leaves municipal utility companies unprepared to enact the necessary cybersecurity counter-measures necessary to prevent or, at least, mitigate attacks. As Miller [1], points out, local governments could benefit from the information that would lead to the early prevention of cyberattacks. Unfortunately, the information is often hidden or never revealed. Although municipalities are obliged to report attacks in a timely fashion, they often avoid reporting attacks to maintain credibility.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions II</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/11/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/11/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities2/</guid><description>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions II Cyberattacks launched on municipal utility companies are similar to attacks in any other industry. However, the potential for OT attacks and the dangers of a major service disruption has raised the stakes. Miller outlines in this article [1] the most common cybersecurity attacks that have affected municipal utility companies. Denial of Service Attacks that stop users from accessing essential networks are typically referred to as denial of service (DoS) or distributed denial of service (DDoS) attacks.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</guid><description>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I In 2021 Jason Miller wrote an article on cybersecurity for municipal utilities stressing that cyber-attacks were increasing every year and greatly impacting a wide range of high-profile targets from governmental agencies to financial and insurance organizations, hospitals and other health facilities, and educational institutions. Of particular concern in many countries, he points out, is the situation on local levels where local governments with municipal utilities are often under-funded with poorly trained staff [1].</description></item><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers Christmas 2022 edition: The second CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_2/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers Christmas 2022 edition: The second CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast We are happy to announce the second CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast with Juha Röning!
Juha is the Coordinator of the CS-AWARE-NEXT project and is Professor of Embedded Systems at the University of Oulu. Juha has also coordinated the original CS-AWARE project.
He has three patents and has published more than 300 papers in the areas of computer vision, robotics, intelligent signal analysis, and software security.</description></item><item><title>Welcome CS-Connect!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/12/15/cs_aware_next_cs_connect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/12/15/cs_aware_next_cs_connect/</guid><description>Welcome CS-Connect! In CS-AWARE-NEXT, the role of our unit, CERICT-Università di Salerno, is to design, develop and evaluate, a collaboration layer for the ecosystem, aimed to support the organisations in their activities toward improved security.
We are actually collecting all the requirements from the use cases and we have had very interesting discussions with the organisations in the ecosystems in Larissa and in Foggia, to find out what is actually needed to ensure adequate support to the ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_1/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast We are happy to announce the first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast with Chris Wills!
Chris is Founder and Member of the Management Board of the CS-AWARE Corporation, and has worked as a member of the CS-AWARE project, leading the socio-technical analysis of the cybersecurity situations in the two major European cities that were partners in the project.
His specialist areas of interest are those of Socio-Technical systems analysis and design of cybersecurity systems, software process in safety critical systems and threat and risk assessment in ITC systems.</description></item><item><title>Startups in Europe – and elsewhere</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/27/cs_aware_next_startups_in_europe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/27/cs_aware_next_startups_in_europe/</guid><description>Startups in Europe – and elsewhere CS-AWARE Corporation is not only one of the partners of the CS-AWARE-NEXT Consortium, but also the main vehicle for the exploitation of all project outcomes and results. The company itself is a successful spin-out of the previous CS-AWARE Innovation Action and considered as a success story because we exhibited commitment to build a sustainable business that will help local public organisations increase their awareness and build capacities to successfully fight with cyber security threats.</description></item><item><title>Turning the Internet into a meaningful (data) space!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/05/cs_aware_next_turning_internet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/05/cs_aware_next_turning_internet/</guid><description>Turning the Internet into a meaningful (data) space! Last week I attended the works of the 1st International Conference on FAIR Digital Objects. One may wonder what FAIR Digital Objects are – and then visit the Web page of the Fair Digital Objects Forum to learn more.
Before entering the details of what FDOs are, it may be worth to spend some little time and explain what FAIR is about. More and more projects and research ‘endeavours’ and ‘ventures’ take it as a prerequisite, that all data to be collected – processed – managed – stored should be FAIR.</description></item><item><title>Events</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 12:42:58 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/events/</guid><description>IEEE International conference on Big Data December 5th, 2023 in Sorrento, Italy Improving Cybersecurity Awareness: Tweet Classification using Multilingual Sentence Embeddings and Contextual Features
Authors: Anastasia Cotov, Carlo Bono, Cinzia Cappiello, Barbara Pernici
CS-AWARE NEXT in TransAI 2023 September 25th, 2023 in Laguna Hills, CA, USA Addressing Critical Issues and Challenges for Dynamic Cybersecurity Management in Organisations and Local/Regional Networks: The CS-AWARE-NEXT Project
Authors: Thomas Schaberreiter, Christian Wieser, Adamantios Koumpis, Christian Luidold, Jerry Andriessen, Cinzia Cappiello, Juha Röning</description></item><item><title>A great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT?</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</guid><description>A great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT? Don&amp;rsquo;t remember if have heard of this incident before, but this could actually be a great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT. It is about the May 2021 ransomware attack on the Health Service Executive (HSE).
At the end of the year 2021, a report was published, that had been commissioned by the Health Services Executive (“HSE”). The report counts about 100 pages – so it is not what one might regard as a convenient reading for an evening discussion.</description></item><item><title>The hard thing about impact</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/13/cs_aware_next_the_hard_thing_about_impact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/13/cs_aware_next_the_hard_thing_about_impact/</guid><description>The hard thing about impact It is now over 8 years that the ‘Hard Thing about Hard Things’ has become a best-selling reader on entrepreneurship. The reason that the audience liked the book may be because the author is not afraid to take for granted that mistakes happen and are an inevitable, or as I prefer to call: a ‘shadow capital’ for every enterprise and venture.
Ben Horowitz, the author of the books, is apart from businessman and investor also active as blogger, devoting time and energy to communicate his ideas and also have them tested with a wider audience.</description></item><item><title>The world is changing…</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/05/cs_aware_next_the_world_is_changing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/05/cs_aware_next_the_world_is_changing/</guid><description>The world is changing… … and startups are considered as agents of change.
Young people now, as well as less young ones, quit their jobs ‘en masse’ and find substance and what each of us may understand in our own, individual ways as ‘meaning in life’ – this is what became to get known as the Great Resignation or the Big Quit.
Many of us have been praised within conservative education and life cultures, feeling that taking risks is worth once you have a big organisation to support you.</description></item><item><title>Another attack…</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/cs_aware_next_another_attack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/cs_aware_next_another_attack/</guid><description>Another attack… Last week, another attack against the UK&amp;rsquo;s National Health Service: this time the target was the NHS 111, a hot line helps people get the right advice and treatment when they urgently need it. So it is not about cinema ticket reservations or something else that one would consider as less important, less critical or less urgent.
You can read about this here and here. So it is nothing new at all – same attacks took place last May in Carinthia in Austria.</description></item><item><title>CS-AWARE Next Project successfully launched!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/08/23/cs_aware_next_launched/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/08/23/cs_aware_next_launched/</guid><description>CS-AWARE Next Project successfully launched!! A new Horizon Europe research project to help organisations and local &amp;amp; regional networks improve cybersecurity awareness and collaboration.
A pan-European consortium led by the University of Oulu in Finland has successfully launched a new Horizon Europe project. The project is called CS-AWARE-NEXT and builds on the legacy of the CS-AWARE project, that was part of the Horizon 2020 Programme, a predecessor of Horizon Europe. The project application has been been successfully evaluated for all three dimensions related to scientific excellence, societal and economic impact and the quality of the research plan implementation.</description></item><item><title>Hello world!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/04/28/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/04/28/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello world! Welcome to join our journey with CS-AWARE-NEXT, a cyber security research project funded by European Union&amp;rsquo;s Horizon Europe research and innovation programme! We will be updating the project&amp;rsquo;s progress and informing you about our arranged events and achieved results in this page with brief blog posts. If you are interested to follow our progress, make sure to follow us on Twitter to get notified when new posts are added so you don&amp;rsquo;t miss them!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/publications/pub1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/publications/pub1/</guid><description>Publication placeholder This is a placeholder</description></item><item><title>Consortium</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/consortium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/consortium/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Want to hear more more about the project? Feel free to contact the project consortium members if you want to hear more about the project or participate in the workshops and events.
For media inquiries, please contact the project coordinator.</description></item><item><title>FIXME</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/1/01/01/cs_aware_next_cert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/1/01/01/cs_aware_next_cert/</guid><description>FIXME FIXME</description></item><item><title>Impact</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_impact/</guid><description>The main vehicle for exploitation of the CS-AWARE-NEXT project results (and thus the project’s pathways to impact) is the CS-AWARE Corporation, which intends to bring the project results to the market in the context of the CS-AWARE cybersecurity awareness and management platform. For further dissemination of project results, academic partners have interest in creating educational and research impact, while SMEs and industry partners have interest in advancing technological achievements and advancing the market introduction of project results.</description></item><item><title>Objectives</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_objectives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_objectives/</guid><description>Objective 1: Improved organisational policy support for dynamic cybersecurity management Description: Provide a cybersecurity management policy framework for organizations to better address the dynamic and constantly changing cybersecurity landscape. This includes a tighter integration between classical risk management and incident management tasks, in order to e.g. be able to more dynamically manage disaster recovery and business continuity after an incident. Collaboration within the organization (between different departments) and with other actors in the multi-level European cybersecurity framework, starting from actors in the local/regional supply chain to actors and authorities on the national/European level, is an important aspect to be addressed by a modern organizational cybersecurity management policy framework.</description></item><item><title>Project</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_overview/</guid><description>Overview The mission of CS-AWARE-NEXT is to address cybersecurity and collaboration within local/regional (intra-organisational and supply chain) networks, in concert with the multi-level European cybersecurity framework as defined by the European cybersecurity strategy. This is achieved through the integration of new methods and tools for provisioning of improved disaster preparedness, multi-level information sharing and advanced AI-based self-healing, to aid in recovery and business continuity of inter-dependent NIS sector organizations in an effort to better address cascading cybersecurity issues.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/project_publications/</guid><description>Reports and Deliverables Here you can find a list of public project reports and deliverables.
Publication link placeholder</description></item><item><title>Terms of Use</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tos/</guid><description>© CS-AWARE-NEXT Consortium, 2022-2024, all rights reserved.
Reproduction is authorised, provided the original source is acknowledged. Any restrictions on use shall be clearly indicated.
The content provided here is for general information purposes. We assume no warranty/liability for the accuracy, currency, completeness and availability of the information/services offered. In particular, no legal claims arising from the use of the information and services accessed may be established. They cannot replace comprehensive legal advice.</description></item></channel></rss>