<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Platform on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/platform/</link><description>Recent content in Platform on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Inside CS-CONNECT: The open-source technology powering cybersecurity collaboration</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/06/24/blog_cs-connect_vol2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/06/24/blog_cs-connect_vol2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At the core of CS-CONNECT stands a clear technical vision: to enable seamless, data-driven collaboration via a customisable, sustainable platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, the CS-CONNECT team selected Mattermost, an open-source collaboration platform renowned for its extensibility, as the foundation. Mattermost’s robust plugin system and active developer community make it ideal for building custom features to meet the unique requirements of cybersecurity collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of CS-CONNECT&amp;rsquo;s key innovations is the HOOD (Hyperlinked Object-Oriented Discussion) methodology. This approach enables users to link specific data points (e.g. a field in a policy or an event in a timeline) directly within chat messages. It&amp;rsquo;s like being able to &amp;lsquo;point&amp;rsquo; at data during a digital conversation, helping teams to maintain context and clarity, even in complex discussions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What is CS-CONNECT? A new approach to cybersecurity collaboration</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/06/18/blog_cs-connect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/06/18/blog_cs-connect/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a world where cyber threats are becoming increasingly sophisticated and
interconnected, collaboration between organisations and regions is essential.
That’s where CS-CONNECT comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed as part of the CS-AWARE NEXT project and funded by the European
Union’s Horizon Europe programme, CS-CONNECT is an innovative platform. Its
main goal is to support local and regional cybersecurity collaboration by offering a
dynamic environment in which organisations can share and review information, co-
create security policies and respond quickly to cybersecurity incidents.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>