<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ransomware on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/ransomware/</link><description>Recent content in Ransomware on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/ransomware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Amateur criminals pose a significant threat to cyberspace</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/10/02/blog_amateur_criminals/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/10/02/blog_amateur_criminals/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amateur criminals who use do-it-yourself solutions to increase their attacks are now an increasing threat for the internet users. Kaspersky’s GReAT (Global Research &amp;amp; Analysis Team) published a report that describes the recent ransomware attacks with the use of code.
The report sheds a light on the tools and the methods that are used by organized ransomware groups and single users. According to its findings the ransomware criminal organisations have a vast variety of tools and samples at their disposal. They often own sample ransomware, while isolated users often use DIY leaked variations to launch their attacks.
The study by Kasperksy reveals recent ransomware attacks, which take advantage of the source code leaks, by allowing the attackers to locate their victims and reproduce fast any malware activity, thus constituting them a significant threat.
Last April, the SEXi team attacked IxMetro, by using a recent ransomware variation called SEXi. This group targets ESXi apps while all the recognized victims used versions of the apps that were not supported.
SEXi uses different ransomware versions for every platform – Bakuk for Linus and Lockbit for Windows. They are, also, the only ones using this Session app for communication, with a unified ID for multiple attacks. This lack of professionalism and the absence of a TOR leak website made them stand out even more.
Source code leaks
Key Group, also known as keygroup777, has used eight different ransomware categories since its founding, April 2022. The techniques and resilience mechanisms that they use evolve with every new variation. The UX- cryptor, for example, used many registry logs for resilience, while Chaos variation had a different approach, that is related to the starting file.
Despite its alternative methods, Key Group is famous for its unprofessional way of work, including the use of a public GitHub repository for communication C2 and Telegram for interaction, my making their monitoring easier.
Kaspersky notes: “the ability to exclude new ransomware has vertically dropped. With digitized ransomware and subsidiaries programs, even young digital criminals pose a significant threat. While the groups that use variation leaks lack high level of professionalism, they owe their efficiency in successful collaboration programs or targeting as can be seen from KeyGroup and SEXi. The publish and leak of ransomware variations are important threats for organisations and citizens alike”.
Source: &lt;a href="https://securelist.com/sexi-key-group-mallox-ransomware/113183/">https://securelist.com/sexi-key-group-mallox-ransomware/113183/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Local and Regional Authorities can improve their ransomware defenses</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/12/19/blog_regional_ransomware_defense/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/12/19/blog_regional_ransomware_defense/</guid><description>&lt;p>A recent study done by the National Association of State CIOs (NASCiO) and Deloitte found in the US 75% of state CISOs view ransomware as a threat. As this Govloop report reported “…there’s good reason for that. A number of factos, the report notes that combine to make local and regional governments particularly vulnerable to this attack”.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>High impact: Ransomeware is capable of causing an organization’s operations to a halt. As an attack it is one of the most likely facing local and regional organizations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easy entry: With commercialization of attacks using “Ransomware-as-a-Service”, even non-technical threat actors are able to profit easily from ransomware operations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Emergence of distributors: Malware families tend to be, the Govloop article points out, prolific information stealers are linked to various ransomware operators.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Clearly local and regional organizations need to revamp their strategies to deal with these challenges:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT?</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</guid><description>&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t remember if have heard of this incident before, but this could actually be a great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT.
It is about the May 2021 ransomware attack on the Health Service Executive (HSE).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the year 2021, a &lt;a href="https://www.hse.ie/eng/services/publications/conti-cyber-attack-on-the-hse-full-report.pdf">report&lt;/a> was published, that had been commissioned by the Health Services Executive (“HSE”). The report counts about 100 pages – so it is not what one might regard as a convenient reading for an evening discussion. However, there are many generic cybersecurity issues that the report raises that are to be addressed in the CS-AWARE-NEXT project&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Another attack…</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/cs_aware_next_another_attack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/cs_aware_next_another_attack/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week, another attack against the UK&amp;rsquo;s National Health Service: this time the target was the NHS 111, a hot line helps people get the right advice and treatment when they urgently need it. So it is not about cinema ticket reservations or something else that one would consider as less important, less critical or less urgent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read about this &lt;a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/health/cyber-attack-nhs-111-b2139188.html">here&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2022/aug/05/nhs-111-expects-delays-after-cyber-attack-causes-system-outage">here&lt;/a>. So it is nothing new at all – same attacks took place last May in Carinthia in Austria. You can also read about this &lt;a href="https://www.derstandard.at/story/2000137884939/im-visier-der-hacker-wie-es-um-oesterreichs-vorbereitung-auf">here&lt;/a> as well.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>