<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elisavet Goutman on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/elisavet-goutman/</link><description>Recent content in Elisavet Goutman on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/elisavet-goutman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New investigation by Kaspersky on Cyber Attacks</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_cyberattacks_kaspersky/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_cyberattacks_kaspersky/</guid><description>New investigation by Kaspersky on Cyber Attacks Kaspersky has recently concluded an investigation into cyber-attacks targeting the industrial sector in Eastern Europe. The investigation has revealed the employment of advanced tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) by threat actors to compromise industrial organizations in the region. Industries such as manufacturing, industrial control system (ICS) engineering and integration have been particularly affected, emphasizing the urgent need for enhanced cybersecurity preparedness.
According to the research a series of targeted attacks was revealed, aiming at data -breach through the creation of a channel with similarities to cases previously reported, such as ExCone, and DexCone, a fact that clearly manifests the participation of APT31 (also known as Judgement Panda and Zirconium).</description></item><item><title>Lessons learnt from cyber-attacks on Greek municipalities</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/10/10/blog_lessions_learnt_greece/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/10/10/blog_lessions_learnt_greece/</guid><description>Lessons learnt from cyber-attacks on Greek municipalities Just how hard is to describe the importance of a service whose value the customers cannot quite comprehend or quantify in order to invest in it in the Greek public sector?
If one had to answer this question, he would have to give many answers, depending on various factors. It is incredibly difficult for an organisation to fully comprehend the need and the importance of cybersecurity service or product when he hasn’t been exposed or harmed by a cyber-attack.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity challenges in Greek companies – Study by EY Greece and Microsoft</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/28/blog_study_ey_greece_microsoft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/28/blog_study_ey_greece_microsoft/</guid><description>Cybersecurity challenges in Greek companies – Study by EY Greece and Microsoft ΕΥ Greece and Microsoft have carried out a study on the challenges concerning cybersecurity in Greece. The study attempts, for the first time in the Greek market, to thoroughly analyse the current national and European legal and regulatory framework of cybersecurity. European regulations, such as NIS, NIS II and CERD, the main legal acts on cybersecurity in Greece (4577/2018, 4961/2022), their field of practice and the next steps for the compliance of the Greek companies with those, are presented in the study.</description></item><item><title>3 ερωτήσεις – 3 απαντήσεις: Our popular CS-AWARE podcast series of 3 questions – 3 answers now in other languages</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_4/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast We start today with a podcast in Greek with Elisavet Goutman, Business Development and Marketing Manager of OTS in Greece.
We are happy to announce the fourth podcast with Elisavet Goutman of OTS Greece. The reason we shall experiment with podcasts in national languages, namely not in English is rather simple: English can be our common working language for Deliverables, and can be ideal for reaching out researchers, but if we truly want to walk the last mile and increase the visibility of the project to a large audience in the participating countries, then the best is to create content in the different national languages.</description></item><item><title>Greece's new Cybersecurity Bill</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/11/greece-new-cybersec-law/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/11/greece-new-cybersec-law/</guid><description>Greece&amp;rsquo;s new Cybersecurity Bill A bill on cyber security, telecommunication privacy issues and personal data has been submitted to the Greek parliament. In particular, the bill aims at “ensuring the necessary balance between privacy protection and national security, within the constitutional frame and in the foundation of the best international policies.” Additionally, the bill strengthens the “citizen’s rights against the threats that are connected to the technological evolution”.
The bill in question deals with issues of counter surveillance with the use of right tools, the foundation of Information Academy and counterintelligence and the setting of a stricter privacy frame.</description></item><item><title>Massive increase in cyber attacks in 2022</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/24/cs_aware_next_massive-cyber/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/24/cs_aware_next_massive-cyber/</guid><description>Massive increase in cyber attacks in 2022 Universities, research centers, state and military services, hospitals, communication infrastructure and banks have received numerous cyberattacks in 2022; and the worst is yet to come.
It is estimated that more than 1.000 cyberattacks per organisation take place throughout the universe, which is 38% more than 2021. In Europe in particular, the average number of attacks per target reached 1.000, with an increase of 26% when compared to 2021.</description></item></channel></rss>