<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CS-AWARE Corporation on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/cs-aware-corporation/</link><description>Recent content in CS-AWARE Corporation on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/cs-aware-corporation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_1/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast We are happy to announce the first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast with Chris Wills!
Chris is Founder and Member of the Management Board of the CS-AWARE Corporation, and has worked as a member of the CS-AWARE project, leading the socio-technical analysis of the cybersecurity situations in the two major European cities that were partners in the project.
His specialist areas of interest are those of Socio-Technical systems analysis and design of cybersecurity systems, software process in safety critical systems and threat and risk assessment in ITC systems.</description></item><item><title>A great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT?</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</guid><description>A great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT? Don&amp;rsquo;t remember if have heard of this incident before, but this could actually be a great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT. It is about the May 2021 ransomware attack on the Health Service Executive (HSE).
At the end of the year 2021, a report was published, that had been commissioned by the Health Services Executive (“HSE”). The report counts about 100 pages – so it is not what one might regard as a convenient reading for an evening discussion.</description></item></channel></rss>