<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Greece on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/greece/</link><description>Recent content in Greece on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/greece/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Greek companies have the weakest cybersecurity</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/05/30/blog_greek_companies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/05/30/blog_greek_companies/</guid><description>&lt;p>Greek businesses have emerged as the weakest link in the European Union when it comes to cybersecurity, ranking last in terms of protective measures against cyberattacks. Just days after Kaspersky released data showing that Greece tops the list as the most dangerous online environment globally, Eurostat figures paint a grim picture of corporate cyber-readiness, placing Greek companies extremely low in the rankings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to the latest Eurostat data, while the majority of companies in the EU have implemented cybersecurity measures, disparities among member-states remain significant. Greek companies stand out negatively, being labeled as the weakest of Europe in terms of implementing cybersecurity protections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cyberattack at Hellenic Open University (HOU): 813GB of personal data leaked</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/05/13/blog_cyberattack_hou/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/05/13/blog_cyberattack_hou/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Hellenic Open University clarifies that this size represents an extremely small percentage, compared to the total volume of data that they maintain, and emphasizes that the investigation continues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The HOU in Greece, has provided clarifications regarding the cyberattack it suffered last October, noting that the investigation on this incident is still ongoing. The cyberattack, which took place on October 25th, resulted in the HOU’s electronic systems being put out of operation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dangerous malware in Greece</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/09/15/blog_dangerous_software/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/09/15/blog_dangerous_software/</guid><description>&lt;p>The last report from Check Point Research, in August 2024, reveals the most recent data on the most prevalent cyberthreats in a global scale but also in Greece. Qbot software was the main threat in Greece, affecting 12.77% of the organisations. FakeUpdates was second, which affected 10.21% of the Greek organisations, while Androgyh0st reached 3.62%. A number of other significant threats include Tofsee (3.19%), Njrat (2,34%), Joker (1,91%), SnakeKeylogger (1,70%) and AsyncRat, which recorded a percentage of 1,70% both in Greece and globally.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Greece's new Cybersecurity Bill</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/11/greece-new-cybersec-law/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 11:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/03/11/greece-new-cybersec-law/</guid><description>&lt;p>A bill on cyber security, telecommunication privacy issues and personal data has been submitted to the Greek parliament. In particular, the bill aims at “ensuring the necessary balance between privacy protection and national security, within the constitutional frame and in the foundation of the best international policies.” Additionally, the bill strengthens the “citizen’s rights against the threats that are connected to the technological evolution”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bill in question deals with issues of counter surveillance with the use of right tools, the foundation of Information Academy and counterintelligence and the setting of a stricter privacy frame. A major part of the bill though is about cybersecurity and the enforcement of the privacy protection. A coordination committee is assembled with the task of breaking down of the related structures. A Unified Reporting Center for Cybersecurity is running in the ministry of Digital Governance. Also, for the first time, a National Plan for Valuation of Technology and Communication Systems hazard levels is structured. It is used for recognition, analysis and valuation of the hazards and their repercussions on the safety of the national technology, information and communication systems. Prior ambiguities in the embedding of this frame for privacy protection were lifted. The ministry of Justice embodies in this bill, a number of suggestions that were made during its consultation and further improvements were made. A number of amendments were carried out and they are outlined below:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>