<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Juho Bruun on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/juho-bruun/</link><description>Recent content in Juho Bruun on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/juho-bruun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New cybersecurity related legislation in Finland</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/12/blog_new_cybersec_legislation_in_finland/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/12/blog_new_cybersec_legislation_in_finland/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Act on the Protection of Infrastructure Critical to Society and on the Improvement of Resilience took effect on 1 July 2025 in Finland. The new legislation imposes requirements on all entities providing services critical to society according to an EU directive. The legislation aims to reinforce national security and societal resilience amid the evolving security threat landscape in the wake of the Russian invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finnish Ministry of the Interior will cooperate with other ministries to identify essential entities in Finland and at the same time renew the national security assessment according to the new legislation. The industried deemed essential include: infrastructure, health, drinking water, wastewater management, digital infrastructure, public administration, space, and the food industry including processing and distribution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CriM 2024</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/11/11/blog_crim24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/11/11/blog_crim24/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The yearly cyber security seminar CriM is upon us once again! We are glad to host three days of expert lectures on this year&amp;rsquo;s topic: CyberSec in Muumimaa - Finnish Cybersecurity in a changing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside with the expert lectures, there is a workshop on TPM 2.0 and a two-afternoon hackathon on AI Security focused on Large Language Models. The 100+ attendants from the industry and University of Oulu will get acquainted with TPM2.0 security, prompt engineering, and the latest LLM security testing tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>