<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Christian Wieser on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/christian-wieser/</link><description>Recent content in Christian Wieser on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/christian-wieser/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CriM 2023</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/10/11/blog_crim23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/10/11/blog_crim23/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Cyber Security Seminar and Workshops (CriM) has been running for 24 years. We are glad to host for three days experts on this year&amp;rsquo;s topic: Supply Chain and Cyber Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mornings are filled with lectures and the afternoon workshops give practical expereince. The attendence is free of charge and 5 ECTS are available for completing the course. Please join us between 14th and 16th of November 2023 here in Oulu.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New Cybersecurity Master's Program in Oulu</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/blog_new_cybersec_curri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/blog_new_cybersec_curri/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity is a new study option based on the research excellence in software security at the University of Oulu. The student specialising in cybersecurity will be able to design, develop, test and evaluate systems, software or hardware for security goals in the ever evolving digital landscape​.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a whole, artificial intelligence and the development of different AI solutions play a role in all four study options. For example, the studies can contribute to various aspects of emerging edge computing and edge AI technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>New Cybersecurity Master's Program in Oulu</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cyber security is a new study option based on the research excellence in software security at the University of Oulu. The student specialising in cyber security will be able to design, develop, test and evaluate systems, software or hardware for security goals in the ever evolving digital landscape​.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a whole, artificial intelligence and the development of different AI solutions play a role in all four study options. For example, the studies can contribute to various aspects of emerging edge computing and edge AI technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CriM -- Cyber Security Seminar and Workshops -- 2022</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/19/cs_aware_next_crim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/19/cs_aware_next_crim/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;During November 2022 we held the Cyber Security Seminar and Workshops in Oulu, Finland. This four days event has been held since 1999 and brings together teachers, researchers, experts, and students of cybersecurity: &lt;a href="https://www.oulu.fi/en/crim"&gt;https://www.oulu.fi/en/crim&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CriM had twelve talks before lunch and three exercises in the afternoon, covering topics from incidence response to password handling. We were especially glad to hear a talk from Bart Preneel, Europe’s most pronounced cryptography expert, who reminded us at the end of his presentation to a quote from Immanuel Kant “Optimism is a moral duty”.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>