<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Line Thorsen Sieg on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/line-thorsen-sieg/</link><description>Recent content in Line Thorsen Sieg on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 17:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/line-thorsen-sieg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The importance of user role definition and access restrictions</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_importance_of_role_definition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_importance_of_role_definition/</guid><description>The importance of user role definition and access restrictions Many of us have seen the cinematic masterpiece called The Lord of the Rings and can recall the scene where Pippin Took touches The Palantír (the glass orb looking thing with the eye of Sauron in it) and thus gave said villain an insight to his mind.
The bad news: Sauron knows everything Pippin knows. The good news: Pippin doesn’t know anything!</description></item><item><title>The legend of The Scottish Thistle - the early version of a socio-technical defence system!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/24/cs_aware_next_scottish_thistle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/24/cs_aware_next_scottish_thistle/</guid><description>The legend of The Scottish Thistle - the early version of a socio-technical defence system! Technology is getting both advanced and effective, but what good does it do if we don’t understand and use it properly? Humans have a long history of using tools to help us make our jobs easier or for keeping us safe. However, technology can only do so much on it’s own. It needs a human touch to fulfil its full potential.</description></item></channel></rss>