<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>critical infrastructure on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/critical-infrastructure/</link><description>Recent content in critical infrastructure on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/critical-infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions II</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/11/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/11/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities2/</guid><description>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions II Cyberattacks launched on municipal utility companies are similar to attacks in any other industry. However, the potential for OT attacks and the dangers of a major service disruption has raised the stakes. Miller outlines in this article [1] the most common cybersecurity attacks that have affected municipal utility companies. Denial of Service Attacks that stop users from accessing essential networks are typically referred to as denial of service (DoS) or distributed denial of service (DDoS) attacks.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</guid><description>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I In 2021 Jason Miller wrote an article on cybersecurity for municipal utilities stressing that cyber-attacks were increasing every year and greatly impacting a wide range of high-profile targets from governmental agencies to financial and insurance organizations, hospitals and other health facilities, and educational institutions. Of particular concern in many countries, he points out, is the situation on local levels where local governments with municipal utilities are often under-funded with poorly trained staff [1].</description></item></channel></rss>