<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OTS on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/ots/</link><description>Recent content in OTS on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 13:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/ots/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Information Society is leading the battle for Cybersecurity</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/18/blog_information_society/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/18/blog_information_society/</guid><description>Information Society is leading the battle for Cybersecurity The Ministry of Digital Governance (MDG) in Greece is implementing a set of projects through Information Society for the protection of public bodies against cyberattacks.
Cybersecurity in the public sector is crucial for safeguarding sensitive information, ensuring the integrity of essential services, and maintaining public trust. Government agencies handle vast amounts of personal data and critical infrastructure, making them prime targets for cyberattacks.</description></item><item><title>New investigation by Kaspersky on Cyber Attacks</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_cyberattacks_kaspersky/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2024/06/11/blog_cyberattacks_kaspersky/</guid><description>New investigation by Kaspersky on Cyber Attacks Kaspersky has recently concluded an investigation into cyber-attacks targeting the industrial sector in Eastern Europe. The investigation has revealed the employment of advanced tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) by threat actors to compromise industrial organizations in the region. Industries such as manufacturing, industrial control system (ICS) engineering and integration have been particularly affected, emphasizing the urgent need for enhanced cybersecurity preparedness.
According to the research a series of targeted attacks was revealed, aiming at data -breach through the creation of a channel with similarities to cases previously reported, such as ExCone, and DexCone, a fact that clearly manifests the participation of APT31 (also known as Judgement Panda and Zirconium).</description></item></channel></rss>