<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alex Papanikolaou on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/alex-papanikolaou/</link><description>Recent content in Alex Papanikolaou on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/alex-papanikolaou/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Threat Maps – Spotting Cyberattacks Before They Happen</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/29/blog_threat_maps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/29/blog_threat_maps/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When most people think about cyberattacks, they picture a sudden breach — an email hack, stolen credit card numbers, or a ransomware note popping up on a screen. But in reality, many attacks leave behind digital clues long before they strike. That’s where threat maps come in. These interactive tools show where attacks are happening around the world in real time, giving cybersecurity experts a bird’s-eye view of the global threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Inside the Mind of a Hacker: What Cyberthreat Intelligence Reveals</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/28/blog_inside_the_mind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/28/blog_inside_the_mind/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how cybersecurity experts know what hackers are planning? The answer lies in cyberthreat intelligence, a behind-the-scenes field that’s less about flashy firewalls and more about detective work. It’s like digital espionage, where analysts gather clues from hacker forums, dark web marketplaces, malware samples, and even leaked chats to understand who the attackers are, what they want, and how they operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyberthreat intelligence (CTI) helps organisations move from reacting to attacks to preventing them. By studying patterns in past breaches and monitoring hacker chatter, analysts can anticipate which industries or vulnerabilities might be targeted next. For example, if threat actors start discussing exploits in popular remote work tools, CTI teams can alert companies to patch those systems before an attack happens. This proactive approach saves time, money, and trust.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Threat Intel Tracks Emerging Scams</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/27/blog_threat_intel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2025/08/27/blog_threat_intel/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One might think online scams just appear out of thin air, but in reality, many of them start brewing in the darkest corners of the internet. On hidden websites and forums known collectively as “The Dark Web”, hackers and cybercriminals trade stolen data, sell scam templates, and even share tips on how to trick people more effectively. Cyberthreat intelligence (CTI) experts spend time monitoring these spaces to spot threats before they reach email inboxes or social media feeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Supervised vs automated response to cyberthreats</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/23/cs_aware_next_supervised_vs_automated_response/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/23/cs_aware_next_supervised_vs_automated_response/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cyberthreats are continually becoming more sophisticated, thus creating a demand for an equally advanced threat detection and response. Detection of cyberthreats can very much benefit from the adoption of AI, as it is able to detect attack patterns and perform correlations among various security-related events. However, when it comes to incident handling, a fully AI-enabled approach may actually cause more harm than good, due to the critical human factors involved.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>