<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Source on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/open-source/</link><description>Recent content in Open Source on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CS-AWARE NEXT received support from the Horizon Standardisation Booster</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_standardisation_booster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_standardisation_booster/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our project had the opportunity to receive advisory services by the HSbooster.eu that is a European Commission initiative aiming to provide expert services to European projects to help them to increase and valorise project results by contributing to the creation of new or improvement of existing standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As presented in the final expert report, ‘the whole HSBooster consultancy process with CS-AWARE NEXT went fluently and there was great support by the team of CS-AWARE NEXT to identify a suitable standardisation strategy for their envisioned project results’. It is also mentioned that ‘the CS-AWARE NEXT project is on a very good track’ and that we ‘have identified a clear and actionable target’ in terms of, amongst others, ‘adding an extension to the OASIS STIX public repository’. There is no doubt that this might potentially ‘pave the way for future standardisation impacts, i.e., the inclusion of the extension in the official STIX OASIS standard’.
Standardisation is, as known to all of us that have been involved in one or some other way in such a process, a long shot, but also well worth trying.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enhancing your security with open-source tools</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_enhancing_security_open_source/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_enhancing_security_open_source/</guid><description>&lt;p>With cybersecurity gaining increased attention in Italy, it has emerged as the top priority for digital investment among businesses in 2023. Notably, both large enterprises and SMEs recognize the significance of robust cybersecurity measures. Recent data reveals that a staggering 61% of organisations with over 250 employees have chosen to boost their cybersecurity budgets in the past year. Moreover, the Italian cybersecurity market is projected to witness remarkable growth, reaching a value of 1.86 billion euros in 2022, reflecting an exceptional acceleration of +18% compared to the previous year. In this article, we delve into the realm of monitoring and analysis, exploring the potential of open-source solutions to strengthen cybersecurity defences and address the evolving challenges faced by Italian organisations.
Fluentd&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>