<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alsu Shakiryanova on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/alsu-shakiryanova/</link><description>Recent content in Alsu Shakiryanova on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/authors/alsu-shakiryanova/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Cybersecuirty Master's Program in Oulu</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/09/01/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</guid><description>New Cybersecuirty Master&amp;rsquo;s Program in Oulu Cyber security is a new study option based on the research excellence in software security at the University of Oulu. The student specialising in cyber security will be able to design, develop, test and evaluate systems, software or hardware for security goals in the ever evolving digital landscape​.
As a whole, artificial intelligence and the development of different AI solutions play a role in all four study options.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing your security with open-source tools</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_enhancing_security_open_source/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/08/29/blog_enhancing_security_open_source/</guid><description>Enhancing your security with open-source tools With cybersecurity gaining increased attention in Italy, it has emerged as the top priority for digital investment among businesses in 2023. Notably, both large enterprises and SMEs recognize the significance of robust cybersecurity measures. Recent data reveals that a staggering 61% of organisations with over 250 employees have chosen to boost their cybersecurity budgets in the past year. Moreover, the Italian cybersecurity market is projected to witness remarkable growth, reaching a value of 1.</description></item></channel></rss>