<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>all on CS-AWARE-NEXT</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/categories/all/</link><description>Recent content in all on CS-AWARE-NEXT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cs-aware-next.github.io/categories/all/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Article 15- 4961/2022 National Organisation for Cybersecurity Certification</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/23/cs_aware_next_scottish_thistle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/23/cs_aware_next_scottish_thistle/</guid><description>The legend of The Scottish Thistle - the early version of a socio-technical defence system! Technology is getting both advanced and effective, but what good does it do if we don’t understand and use it properly? Humans have a long history of using tools to help us make our jobs easier or for keeping us safe. However, technology can only do so much on it’s own. It needs a human touch to fulfil its full potential.</description></item><item><title>Article 15- 4961/2022 National Organisation for Cybersecurity Certification</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/23/cs_aware_next_template/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/23/cs_aware_next_template/</guid><description>Article 15- 4961/2022 National Organisation for Cybersecurity Certification The General Administration for Cybersecurity of the Ministry of Digital Governance is designated as the National Institution for Cybersecurity Certification, according to the article 58 of the Regulation 2019/881 of the European Parliament and the Board of the 17th April 2019 regarding ENISA (European Union Agency for Cybersecurity) and the cybersecurity certification in the information technology and communication field for the annulment of the regulation (EU 526/2013 (L151).</description></item><item><title>Storytelling Workshops 2022</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/20/cs_aware_next_2023_storytelling_ws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/20/cs_aware_next_2023_storytelling_ws/</guid><description>Storytelling Workshops 2022 We have organised storytelling workshops in the two pilot sites of the project: the municipalities of Larissa and Foggia. Representatives of multiple public and private organisations came together for four days for these workshops that were organised by our project.
During the workshop, participants shared stories about their experiences with cybersecurity in their organisations, and, in addition, discussed real world examples of cyberattacks that had serious implications on a region, or, the term we like to use, on an entire ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity – a case for advanced decision models</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/08/cs_aware_next_decision_models/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/02/08/cs_aware_next_decision_models/</guid><description>Cybersecurity – a case for advanced decision models Advanced attacks demand advanced countermeasures. On a technical level there already is an elevated level of awareness and readiness. That is why in a first wave of attacks criminals usually focus on tricking users into opening up systems for them . While this has now been the rule for at least over a decade, the way in which these attacks are prepared now follow an almost military style approach.</description></item><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers: Starting up for 2023 with a discussion on ‘AI, the Universe and Everything’ with two Datrix C-level executives</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_3/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers: Starting up for 2023 with a discussion on ‘AI, the Universe and Everything’ with two Datrix C-level executives We are happy to announce the third podcast with Pierluigi Vacca and Matteo Bregonzio of Datrix, Italy.
Pierluigi Vacca, after a 3-year experience with Google USA as Search Quality Evaluator (analysis of search queries and site positioning to improve the Google algorithm) in 2004 he took part in the start-up of Google Italy as manager of Italian and international key accounts, connecting activities as marketing &amp;amp; communication strategies, data intelligence and customers acquisition/retention.</description></item><item><title>Data poisoning attacks</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/25/cs_aware_next_data_poisoning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/25/cs_aware_next_data_poisoning/</guid><description>Data poisoning attacks Data poisoning is an increasingly important security concern for Machine Learning (ML) systems. As machine learning models are becoming more prevalent in our lives, they are also becoming more vulnerable to malicious attacks. Data poisoning attacks are one of the most insidious and difficult-to-detect kinds of threats on ML models.
Data poisoning is a type of adversarial attack in which a cybercriminal injects malicious data into a machine learning model.</description></item><item><title>Massive increase in cyber attacks in 2022</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/24/cs_aware_next_massive-cyber/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/24/cs_aware_next_massive-cyber/</guid><description>Massive increase in cyber attacks in 2022 Universities, research centers, state and military services, hospitals, communication infrastructure and banks have received numerous cyberattacks in 2022; and the worst is yet to come.
It is estimated that more than 1.000 cyberattacks per organisation take place throughout the universe, which is 38% more than 2021. In Europe in particular, the average number of attacks per target reached 1.000, with an increase of 26% when compared to 2021.</description></item><item><title>CriM -- Cyber Security Seminar and Workshops -- 2022</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/18/cs_aware_next_crim/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/18/cs_aware_next_crim/</guid><description>CriM - Engaging the next generation of cyber security professionals During November 2022 we held the Cyber Security Seminar and Workshops in Oulu, Finland. This four days event has been held since 1999 and brings together teachers, researchers, experts, and students of cybersecurity: https://www.oulu.fi/en/crim.
CriM had twelve talks before lunch and three exercises in the afternoon, covering topics from incidence response to password handling. We were especially glad to hear a talk from Bart Preneel, Europe’s most pronounced cryptography expert, who reminded us at the end of his presentation to a quote from Immanuel Kant “Optimism is a moral duty”.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions III</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/17/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/17/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities3/</guid><description>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions III Failing to understand the gravity of the potential effects of a power grid attack leaves municipal utility companies unprepared to enact the necessary cybersecurity counter-measures necessary to prevent or, at least, mitigate attacks. As Miller [1], points out, local governments could benefit from the information that would lead to the early prevention of cyberattacks. Unfortunately, the information is often hidden or never revealed. Although municipalities are obliged to report attacks in a timely fashion, they often avoid reporting attacks to maintain credibility.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions II</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/11/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/11/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities2/</guid><description>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions II Cyberattacks launched on municipal utility companies are similar to attacks in any other industry. However, the potential for OT attacks and the dangers of a major service disruption has raised the stakes. Miller outlines in this article [1] the most common cybersecurity attacks that have affected municipal utility companies. Denial of Service Attacks that stop users from accessing essential networks are typically referred to as denial of service (DoS) or distributed denial of service (DDoS) attacks.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2023/01/02/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_for_public_utilities1/</guid><description>Cybersecurity For Public Utilities Solutions I In 2021 Jason Miller wrote an article on cybersecurity for municipal utilities stressing that cyber-attacks were increasing every year and greatly impacting a wide range of high-profile targets from governmental agencies to financial and insurance organizations, hospitals and other health facilities, and educational institutions. Of particular concern in many countries, he points out, is the situation on local levels where local governments with municipal utilities are often under-funded with poorly trained staff [1].</description></item><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers Christmas 2022 edition: The second CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_2/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers Christmas 2022 edition: The second CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast We are happy to announce the second CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast with Juha Röning!
Juha is the Coordinator of the CS-AWARE-NEXT project and is Professor of Embedded Systems at the University of Oulu. Juha has also coordinated the original CS-AWARE project.
He has three patents and has published more than 300 papers in the areas of computer vision, robotics, intelligent signal analysis, and software security.</description></item><item><title>Welcome CS-Connect!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/12/15/cs_aware_next_cs_connect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/12/15/cs_aware_next_cs_connect/</guid><description>Welcome CS-Connect! In CS-AWARE-NEXT, the role of our unit, CERICT-Università di Salerno, is to design, develop and evaluate, a collaboration layer for the ecosystem, aimed to support the organisations in their activities toward improved security.
We are actually collecting all the requirements from the use cases and we have had very interesting discussions with the organisations in the ecosystems in Larissa and in Foggia, to find out what is actually needed to ensure adequate support to the ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/podcasts/podcast_1/</guid><description>3 questions – 3 answers: The first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast We are happy to announce the first CS-AWARE-NEXT Podcast with Chris Wills!
Chris is Founder and Member of the Management Board of the CS-AWARE Corporation, and has worked as a member of the CS-AWARE project, leading the socio-technical analysis of the cybersecurity situations in the two major European cities that were partners in the project.
His specialist areas of interest are those of Socio-Technical systems analysis and design of cybersecurity systems, software process in safety critical systems and threat and risk assessment in ITC systems.</description></item><item><title>Startups in Europe – and elsewhere</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/27/cs_aware_next_startups_in_europe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/27/cs_aware_next_startups_in_europe/</guid><description>Startups in Europe – and elsewhere CS-AWARE Corporation is not only one of the partners of the CS-AWARE-NEXT Consortium, but also the main vehicle for the exploitation of all project outcomes and results. The company itself is a successful spin-out of the previous CS-AWARE Innovation Action and considered as a success story because we exhibited commitment to build a sustainable business that will help local public organisations increase their awareness and build capacities to successfully fight with cyber security threats.</description></item><item><title>Turning the Internet into a meaningful (data) space!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/05/cs_aware_next_turning_internet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/11/05/cs_aware_next_turning_internet/</guid><description>Turning the Internet into a meaningful (data) space! Last week I attended the works of the 1st International Conference on FAIR Digital Objects. One may wonder what FAIR Digital Objects are – and then visit the Web page of the Fair Digital Objects Forum to learn more.
Before entering the details of what FDOs are, it may be worth to spend some little time and explain what FAIR is about. More and more projects and research ‘endeavours’ and ‘ventures’ take it as a prerequisite, that all data to be collected – processed – managed – stored should be FAIR.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity infrastructures - 'Ferrari fast and Fiat cheap'</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/27/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/27/cs_aware_next_cybersecurity_infrastructures/</guid><description>Cybersecurity infrastructures - &amp;lsquo;Ferrari fast and Fiat cheap&amp;rsquo; The title of this blog may seem deliberately provocative but it is actually not meant at all as such. We could also have used some other car brand – so we could have named the blog: ‘Why not buy a Porsche and pay the price of a Volkswagen Polo?’ The original ‘Ferrari fast and Fiat cheap’ idea comes from Alberto Savoia and a presentation he made about ‘How to Succeed by Failing ‘Ferrari Fast’’ which you can listen to as a podcast here.</description></item><item><title>A great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT?</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/20/cs_aware_next_a_great_base_scenario/</guid><description>A great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT? Don&amp;rsquo;t remember if have heard of this incident before, but this could actually be a great base scenario for CS-AWARE-NEXT. It is about the May 2021 ransomware attack on the Health Service Executive (HSE).
At the end of the year 2021, a report was published, that had been commissioned by the Health Services Executive (“HSE”). The report counts about 100 pages – so it is not what one might regard as a convenient reading for an evening discussion.</description></item><item><title>The hard thing about impact</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/13/cs_aware_next_the_hard_thing_about_impact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/13/cs_aware_next_the_hard_thing_about_impact/</guid><description>The hard thing about impact It is now over 8 years that the ‘Hard Thing about Hard Things’ has become a best-selling reader on entrepreneurship. The reason that the audience liked the book may be because the author is not afraid to take for granted that mistakes happen and are an inevitable, or as I prefer to call: a ‘shadow capital’ for every enterprise and venture.
Ben Horowitz, the author of the books, is apart from businessman and investor also active as blogger, devoting time and energy to communicate his ideas and also have them tested with a wider audience.</description></item><item><title>The world is changing…</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/05/cs_aware_next_the_world_is_changing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/05/cs_aware_next_the_world_is_changing/</guid><description>The world is changing… … and startups are considered as agents of change.
Young people now, as well as less young ones, quit their jobs ‘en masse’ and find substance and what each of us may understand in our own, individual ways as ‘meaning in life’ – this is what became to get known as the Great Resignation or the Big Quit.
Many of us have been praised within conservative education and life cultures, feeling that taking risks is worth once you have a big organisation to support you.</description></item><item><title>Another attack…</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/cs_aware_next_another_attack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/09/01/cs_aware_next_another_attack/</guid><description>Another attack… Last week, another attack against the UK&amp;rsquo;s National Health Service: this time the target was the NHS 111, a hot line helps people get the right advice and treatment when they urgently need it. So it is not about cinema ticket reservations or something else that one would consider as less important, less critical or less urgent.
You can read about this here and here. So it is nothing new at all – same attacks took place last May in Carinthia in Austria.</description></item><item><title>CS-AWARE Next Project successfully launched!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/08/23/cs_aware_next_launched/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/08/23/cs_aware_next_launched/</guid><description>CS-AWARE Next Project successfully launched!! A new Horizon Europe research project to help organisations and local &amp;amp; regional networks improve cybersecurity awareness and collaboration.
A pan-European consortium led by the University of Oulu in Finland has successfully launched a new Horizon Europe project. The project is called CS-AWARE-NEXT and builds on the legacy of the CS-AWARE project, that was part of the Horizon 2020 Programme, a predecessor of Horizon Europe. The project application has been been successfully evaluated for all three dimensions related to scientific excellence, societal and economic impact and the quality of the research plan implementation.</description></item><item><title>Hello world!</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/04/28/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/2022/04/28/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello world! Welcome to join our journey with CS-AWARE-NEXT, a cyber security research project funded by European Union&amp;rsquo;s Horizon Europe research and innovation programme! We will be updating the project&amp;rsquo;s progress and informing you about our arranged events and achieved results in this page with brief blog posts. If you are interested to follow our progress, make sure to follow us on Twitter to get notified when new posts are added so you don&amp;rsquo;t miss them!</description></item><item><title>FIXME</title><link>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/1/01/01/cs_aware_next_cert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cs-aware-next.github.io/blog/1/01/01/cs_aware_next_cert/</guid><description>FIXME FIXME</description></item></channel></rss>